# PAOLA CASCANTE-BONILLA

Rice Hall 430, 85 Engineer's Way, Charlottesville, VA 22903 | +1(434)282-9540 | pc9za@virginia.edu

#### **SUMMARY**

I am a Ph.D. student of Computer Science at the University of Virginia. My research relies on the intersection between Computer Vision and Natural Language Processing. I am particularly interested on analyzing and applying algorithms to understand how images and text can model complex patterns related to human interactions and their potential effects on everyday life. More recently, I've been focused in self-supervised learning and meta-learning. Previously I spent 10 years working as a Software Engineer at different Tech Companies.

## **EDUCATION**

Aug 2018 – Ph.D. in Computer Science, *University of Virginia*.

present Charlottesville, Virginia, USA.

2002-2007 / B.Sc in Computer Engineering, Tecnológico de Costa Rica.

2016-2018 Cartago, Costa Rica.

#### **PRE-PRINTS**

Moviescope: Large-scale Analysis of Movies using Multiple Modalities.
Paola Cascante-Bonilla, Kalpathy Sitaraman, Mengjia Luo, Vicente Ordonez.

Curriculum Labeling: Self-paced Pseudo-Labeling for Semi-Supervised Learning Paola Cascante-Bonilla, Fuwen Tan, Yanjun Qi, Vicente Ordonez.

## **PUBLICATIONS**

Drill-down: Interactive Retrieval of Complex Scenes using Natural Language Queries
Fuwen Tan, Paola Cascante-Bonilla, Xiaoxiao Guo, Hui Wu, Song Feng, Vicente Ordonez.
Conf. on Neural Information Processing Systems. NeurIPS 2019. Vancouver, Canada. December 2019.

Chat-crowd: A Dialog-based Platform for Visual Layout Composition.

Paola Cascante-Bonilla, Xuwang Yin, Vicente Ordonez, Song Feng. North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics. NAACL 2019. System Demonstrations. Minneapolis, Minnesota. June 2019.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## December 2012 – July 2018

# Senior Software Engineer/Tech Lead, N3 Results

In charge of the Microsoft Platform Ready Platform, an application readiness and validation compliance with certification requirements for most of the Microsoft technologies. Worked mainly with C#, WCF, SQL, MVC and JavaScript. Also worked on Data Mining.

# February 2010 – October 2012

#### Mid Software Engineer, Growth Acceleration Partners

.NET team: Back-end developer, worked with C#, ASP, MVC, WCF, REST-SOAP, NoSQL, (Cassandra, Thrift, Lucandra, Phelops) and MS SQL 2008.

Mobile team: worked with Android, iOS and RIM (Blackberry).

# November 2009 – February 2010

## Software Engineer, Intel

Worked as a Contractor giving support in 2 projects. Worked with WPF, WCF, Microsoft Visual Studio 2008 (C#, ASP), Oracle, MS SSQL 2008 and Infragistics.

# July 2008 – November 2009

#### Software Engineer, Exactus Costa Rica, Softland Latinoamerica

Core developer in the department of Technology and Investigation. Worked with Microsoft CRM 3.0 and 4.0, Microsoft Visual Studio 2003, 2005 and 2008 (C#, ASP), Sql Server 2005, Oracle, Centura, XML, HTML, JavaScript, Exactus ERP.

# May 2007 – July 2008

#### System Analyst, Instituto Tecnológico de Costa Rica

Developer in "Planilla Presupuestaria" (Payment System) project using ASP.NET, C#, HTML, JavaScript, AJAX, SQL Server, Microsoft Visual SourceSafe. Analyst / Developer in "Financiamiento a Estudiantes del ITCR" (Financial Aid for University Students System)

## **TEACHING**

Teaching Assistant. CS 6501-003: Deep Learning for Visual Recognition - Spring 2020. Teaching Assistant. CS 4501-008: Introduction to Computer Vision - Fall 2019.

#### **AWARDS**

NeurIPS Travel Award.